



# Objective

A technical director position in animation or visual effects, using my experience in problem solving, delivering shows, and simplifying the complex.

#### Profile

Look Development TD / Lighting TD / Generalist

Lighting, shaders, pipeline development, scripting, GUIs, rendering, compositing, modeling, texture painting, UVs

Software experience: Katana, Arnold, V-Ray, Renderman (proprietary and Renderman Studio pipelines), Maya, Python, MEL, mental ray, Nuke, Shake

# **Work History**

Industrial Light & Magic 3/2014 - present Senior Lighting Technical Director

Hero character lighting for plate integration

Look development with physically based shaders

Sony Pictures Imageworks 2/2013 - 2/2014

Look Development / Lighting

Photorealistic and animated feature lighting using a Katana and Arnold pipeline

Final compositing in stereo

Digital Domain 1/2011 - 2/2013 Look Development / Lighting

Hero character and prop look development

Look development using DD's first Katana pipeline, working closely with pipeline TDs to test the workflow

Shot lighting using both pass-based Renderman pipeline, and a physically-based Arnold pipeline

ImageMovers Digital 9/2008 - 12/2010

Look Development Technical Director

Look development on hero characters, costumes, and all crowd and background characters

Wrote workflow enhancement scripts for the surfacing department, including a user-friendly GUI for assembling assets from multiple departments into a ready-to-render turntable

## The Jim Henson Company 6/2005 - 8/2008

Lead Technical Director / Look Development / Pipeline Developer

Worked closely with art directors to develop CG look for multiple shows

Supervised lighting and texturing teams, reducing render farm memory requirements by 50% with custom optimization tools

Developed pipeline, baking, rendering and scene assembly tools

#### Gnomon School of Visual Effects 4/2008 - 9/2008

Instructor / Look Development

Created and instructed Gnomon's first Look Development curriculum

Designed a class wiki where students received continually updated notes and answers to questions

## Education

Gnomon School of Visual Effects - CG Certificate (3/2003-12/2004)